<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Jagadeesh Mummana | Portfolio</title><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Jagadeesh Mummana | Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/</guid><description>GPBOT - Basic Sensor based General Purpose AMR Do checkout : Basic Line Following Robot Obstacle Avoidance Robot Wall Follower Robot Differential Drive Robot Name GPBOT Description This 4-wheeled robot is equipped with GPS, IMU, LiDAR, Distance Sensors, and a 2-DOF camera (using linear and rotary actuators).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/diffdrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/diffdrive/</guid><description>Differential Drive Robot Simulation Name Differential Drive Robot Description A custom-built robot featuring a differential drive system that calculates its position and movement based on wheel rotations Start June 2024 Repository DDR🔗 Type Individual Level Beginner Skills Simulation, Programming Tools Used Webots, Python Current Status On Hold This repository contains the simulation of a Differential Drive Robot, built from scratch, which uses basic odometry to track its position.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/lfr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/lfr/</guid><description>Line Follower Robot Name LFRBOT Description This project features a robot that follows a line using basic sensors.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/obstacle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/obstacle/</guid><description>Obstacle Avoidance Robot Name Obstacle Avoidance Robot Description A robot equipped with basic sensors that detects obstacles and changes direction to avoid collisions without using advanced algorithms Start June 2024 Repository OAR🔗 Type Individual Level Beginner Skills Simulation, Programming Tools Used Webots, Python Current Status On Hold This project simulates a line-following robot using the Webots robotics simulator.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/wallfollow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/wallfollow/</guid><description>Wall Follower Robot Simulation Name Wall Follower Robot Description The wall-following robot travels along walls in a maze.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/improve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/improve/</guid><description>ImProVe: IMage PROcessing using VErilog Do checkout : NEural NEtwork in VERilog Name ImProVe Description ImProVe (Image Processing using Verilog) is a project focused on implementing image processing techniques using Verilog.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/improve/fixed-point/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/improve/fixed-point/</guid><description>Fixed-Point Conversion Report for EMNIST Neural Network Introduction This report describes how I transitioned the EMNIST neural network implementation from floating-point arithmetic to fixed-point representation.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/improve/never/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/improve/never/</guid><description>NeVer: NEural NEtwork in VERilog Do Checkout Main Project: ImProVe: IMage PROcessing using VErilog Name NeVer Description NeVer implements a neural network in Verilog for better hardware acceleration of image processing tasks Start 28 Feb 2025 Repository NeVer🔗 Type Individual Level Beginner Skills Image Processing, HDL, Computer Vision, Programming, ML Tools Used Verilog, Icarus, Perl, TCL, Quartus, C++, Python, NumPy Current Status Ongoing (Active) Progress - Implemented detection of MNIST digits (0-9) - Added support for EMNIST, enabling classification of 62 character classes - Integrated real-time inference with a Tkinter-based character drawing interface, achieving approx 1.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/isro-anav/challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/isro-anav/challenge/</guid><description>For complete official details and documentation, visit the ISRO IRoC-U2025.
IRoC-U 2025 – Technical Challenge Summary Challenge Overview Design and demonstrate an Autonomous Navigation System for an Aerial Vehicle (ANAV) that can function in a simulated Martian environment without any external navigation aids like GNSS, pseudolites, or reflectors.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/isro-anav/simulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/isro-anav/simulation/</guid><description>Simulation of Martian Arena in Webots for Autonomous Drone Testing Introduction To develop and evaluate autonomous drone navigation algorithms in a Mars-like environment, we replicated a Martian surface arena within the Webots simulation platform.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/never/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/never/</guid><description>NeVer: NEural NEtwork in VERilog Do Checkout Main Project: ImProVe: IMage PROcessing using VErilog Name NeVer Description NeVer implements a neural network in Verilog for better hardware acceleration of image processing tasks Start 28 Feb 2025 Repository NeVer🔗 Type Individual Level Beginner Skills Image Processing, HDL, Computer Vision, Programming, ML Tools Used Verilog, Icarus, Perl, TCL, Quartus, Python, NumPy Current Status Ongoing (Active) Progress - Implemented detection of MNIST digits (0-9) - Added support for EMNIST, enabling classification of 62 character classes - Integrated real-time inference with a Tkinter-based character drawing interface, achieving approx 1.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/pidc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/pidc/</guid><description>PIDC - PID Controller using OpAmps Name PIDC Description Implemented a PID controller using operational amplifiers to regulate system response and maintain desired performance.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/prosarm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/prosarm/</guid><description>PR057H371C4RM Name PR057H371C4RM Description A simple prosthetic arm that utilizes servo motors to create tension in strings, replicating the function of human tendons to achieve realistic finger motion.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/protocols/i2c_code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/protocols/i2c_code/</guid><description>MASTER `timescale 1ns / 1ps // Main module declaration module i2c_master( input wire clk, // System clock input wire rst, // Reset signal input wire [6:0] addr, // 7-bit I2C slave address input wire [7:0] data_in, // Data to send to slave in write mode input wire enable, // Start signal for I2C communication input wire rw, // Read/Write control (0 for write, 1 for read) output reg [7:0] data_out, // Data received from slave in read mode output wire ready, // Indicates when the master is ready for a new transaction inout i2c_sda, // I2C data line (SDA) - bidirectional inout wire i2c_scl // I2C clock line (SCL) - bidirectional ); // Define states for I2C master FSM localparam IDLE = 0; localparam START = 1; localparam ADDRESS = 2; localparam READ_ACK = 3; localparam WRITE_DATA = 4; localparam WRITE_ACK = 5; localparam READ_DATA = 6; localparam READ_ACK2 = 7; localparam STOP = 8; localparam DIVIDE_BY = 4; // Clock divider to generate I2C clock from system clock reg [7:0] state; // Current state of the FSM reg [7:0] saved_addr; // Stores the 7-bit address and RW bit for the current transaction reg [7:0] saved_data; // Data to be sent in write transactions reg [7:0] counter; // Bit counter for data/address transmission reg [7:0] counter2 = 0; // Divider counter for generating i2c_clk reg write_enable; // Controls whether the master drives SDA line reg sda_out; // Data to output on SDA line when write_enable is 1 reg i2c_scl_enable = 0; // Controls the state of the i2c_scl line (enabled or high) reg i2c_clk = 1; // Internal I2C clock signal // Ready signal is high when the master is idle and not in reset assign ready = ((rst == 0) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; (state == IDLE)) ?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/protocols/i2cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/protocols/i2cv/</guid><description>I2C Protocol Verilog Implementation using FSM Name I2C Protocol Description Verilog Implementation of I2C Protocol using Finite State Machine (FSM) design Start 06 Nov 2024 Repository I2CV🔗 Type Individual Level Beginner Skills HDL, Protocols, Programming Tools Used Verilog, Icarus, Xilinx Current Status On Hold This project implements the I2C protocol in Verilog with various versions and configurations.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/rubec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/rubec/</guid><description>RU83C: Rubik&amp;rsquo;s Cube Solving Robot Name RU83C Description Rubik&amp;rsquo;s Cube-solving robot using Kociemba algorithm, featuring computer vision for state detection, mechanical design for cube manipulation, and electronics for execution.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/shopping-cart-bot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/shopping-cart-bot/</guid><description>Shopping Cart Bot Name Shopping Cart Bot Description The Shopping Cart Bot is a robotics project designed to automate the shopping experience by utilizing computer vision and autonomous navigation.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/tlcv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/tlcv/</guid><description>TRAFFIC LIGHT CONTROLLER 🚦 Name TLC using Verilog Description Verilog Implementation of Traffic Light Controller Start 05 Apr 2024 Repository TLCV🔗 Type Individual Level Beginner Skills HDL, Programming Tools Used Verilog, Icarus, Xilinx Current Status On Hold The original version, which utilizes FSM, is currently on hold.</description></item><item><title>ANAV for Martian Surface Exploration</title><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/isro-anav/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/isro-anav/</guid><description>ANAV for Martian Surface Exploration
Name ISRO-ANAV Description The designed ANAV is a sub-2 kg rotorcraft built for GNSS-denied environments, capable of autonomous take-off, terrain scanning, safe landing, and return.</description></item><item><title>Basic Sensor-Based Mobile Robots</title><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/subprojects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/gpbot/subprojects/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Verilog HDL Toolkit for Image Processing and Pattern Recognition</title><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/improve/subprojects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/projects/improve/subprojects/</guid><description>Verilog HDL Toolkit for Image Processing and Pattern Recognition Duration: Individual, Ongoing
Tools: Verilog (Icarus Verilog, Xilinx Vivado) | C++ &amp;amp; Python (OpenCV, NumPy, Tkinter) | Scripting (TCL.</description></item></channel></rss>