<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PID1 on Jagadeesh Mummana | Portfolio</title><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/pid1/</link><description>Recent content in PID1 on Jagadeesh Mummana | Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 05:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/pid1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kociemba’s Algorithm – The Two-Phase Breakthrough #PID1.5</title><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/kociembas-alg-the-2-phase-breakthrough/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/kociembas-alg-the-2-phase-breakthrough/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kociemba’s algorithm revolutionizes Rubik’s Cube solving by efficiently navigating the immense complexity of the cube’s state space using advanced mathematical tools from &lt;strong>group theory&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>heuristic search&lt;/strong>. This two-phase method strikes a balance between &lt;strong>tractability&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>optimality&lt;/strong>, making it a cornerstone of computational puzzle solving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Do Computers Come into the Art of Solving Puzzles? #PID1.4</title><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/computers-in-the-art-of-solving-puzzles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/computers-in-the-art-of-solving-puzzles/</guid><description>&lt;p>Throughout history, puzzles have intrigued the human mind, not merely for entertainment but for the challenge they pose to logic, creativity, and persistence. From ancient labyrinths to Sudoku and the Rubik’s Cube, solving a puzzle often feels like an art — but beneath that art lies a surprising amount of structure. And where there is structure, computers can often outperform intuition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mathematics Behind the Rubik's Cube #PID1.3</title><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/mathematics-behind-rubiks-cube/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/mathematics-behind-rubiks-cube/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Rubik’s Cube is not just a puzzle; it’s a deep mathematical object grounded in group theory, combinatorics, and geometry. Understanding the math behind it allows us to grasp why it has 43 quintillion possible states, how we categorize moves, and why some solutions are more efficient than others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solving The Rubiks Cube #PID1.2</title><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/solving-the-rubiks-cube/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/solving-the-rubiks-cube/</guid><description>&lt;!-- **Solving the Rubik’s Cube: A Guide to CFOP, Roux, and ZZ Methods** -->
&lt;p>Solving a Rubik’s Cube isn’t just about memorizing algorithms — it’s about understanding how moves affect the pieces. There are several solving methods, each with its own approach. Some prioritize speed, some focus on efficiency or fewer rotations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mechanics of Rubiks Cube #PID1.1</title><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/mechanics-of-rubiks-cube/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/mechanics-of-rubiks-cube/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Rubik’s Cube is a 3D combination puzzle that has fascinated minds for decades. Invented in &lt;strong>1974 by Ernő Rubik&lt;/strong>, a Hungarian architect and professor, it was originally called the &amp;ldquo;Magic Cube.&amp;rdquo; Designed as a teaching tool to explain 3D movement, it quickly became a global sensation. The challenge? Scramble it, then restore each face to a single color—sounds simple, but millions have struggled (and succeeded) at it since!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Should You Start Solving Puzzles? #PID1.0</title><link>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/why-should-you-start-solving-puzzles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mummanajagadeesh.github.io/blog/why-should-you-start-solving-puzzles/</guid><description>&lt;!-- ##### Puzzles: More Than Just Fun -->
&lt;p>Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a crossword, Sudoku, or a complex jigsaw, puzzles have a unique way of capturing our attention. But what makes solving them feel so rewarding? Beyond the entertainment, puzzles play a significant role in enhancing cognitive abilities, improving problem-solving skills, and offering a tangible sense of accomplishment.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>